Guide to the Laurence MacDaniels papers, [ca. 1915]-1986.
Laurence MacDaniels papers,
- L.H. MacDaniels - American Horticultural Council News Bulletin Working File, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  Correspondence - regarding publication of 1st newsletter; correspondence between Fred P. Lee and Dr. Ray C. Allen, Dr. W.H. Camp, Mr. E.L.D. Seymour regarding bylaws of AHC; copy AHC News June 1953
- Current 1957 Horticultural Council, 1951-1953 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  Correspondence; notes "Teaching for Research in Experimental Station"
- American Horticulutural Council, 1946-1954 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  Correspondence and minutes of meetings - questionnaires and publications
- United Horticulture, 1948-1949 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  Correspondence; brochures from annual meetings Oct. 1947, Oct. 1946, Jan. 1947; membership list Oct. 1947
- AHC News, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  Brochure - AHC meeting Oct. 1954; AHC News Apr. 1954, June 1954, Dec. 1954; list of contributing members 1955
- L.H. MacDaniels - American Horticultural Council Philadelphia, PA Meeting 1953, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  "International Book of Nomenclature for Cultivated Plants: by Committee for Nomenclature of Cultivated Plants, International Botanical Congress, Stockholm, Committee on Nomenclature and Registration, International Horticultural Conference London 1952 - various correspondence, newsletters, printouts 1953
- American Society for Horticultural Society UNESCO Conference Jan. 27-31, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  Correspondence and printouts regarding conference.
- Association for the Arnold Arboretum, 1954-1956 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  Correspondence; membership lists; controversy on Arboretum Dispute with Harvard 1953-1956
- West Hill Civic Association, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Near East Foundation, 1942-1943 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  Correspondence regarding proposed trip to Greece, Syria, Lebanon, et cetera.
- Co-op Consumer's Society, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  Suggested list of nominees to Board of Directors: Jan. 1952
- National Research Council - ASHS 1940, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- New York - March 9. 1953, 1953-03-09 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  AHC minutes; newsletters; bylaws revision; budget reports
- American Horticultural Council News - April Issue, June Issue; Sept. Issue - L.H. MacDaniels March 20, 1953, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  Correspondence; news releases; President message to 7th Horticultural Congress - 6 June 1953
- American Horticultural Council - American Horticultural Council News - Feb. Issue; Dec. 1952-Jan. 1953, 1952-1953 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  Correspondence; minutes of informal meeting- 6 Jan. 1953, copy of Aims and Activities of AHC Oct. 1952 with 1st draft
- American Horticultural Council Correspondence Directors 1952-1953, 1952-1953 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- American Horticultural Council - Mrs. Hull, President Organizational Material - Minutes, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  Minutes of various meetings; correspondence with Hull and Laurence H. MacDaniels
- American Horticultural Council Donald Watson, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  Correspondence December 1953
- American Horticultural Council Flower Color Detector, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  Correspondence regarding Flower Color Detector; Copy of "What the Experts Say about the Flower Color Detector of the American Horticultural Council"
- American Institute of Biological Sciences, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  Correspondence; constitution and bylaws; pamphlets; joint statement of American Association for the Advancement of Science anf American Society of Biological Sciences; newsletter
- American Society of Biological Sciences Bulletins - Marked Copies, Date Unknown (Box 3, Folder 35)
- American Institute of Biological Sciences, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  Correspondence with Professor Evrett C. Albutton
- American Institute of Biological Sciences, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  Convention 1952 Room Assignment Data, et cetera, Needs of Societies
- American Institute of Biological Sciences, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  1952 Room Assignments -Correspondence from Societies and with Building Custodians - survey of rooms
- American Institute of Biological Sciences - Cornell 1952 Meetings, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  Correspondence with Dr. Howlett
- American Institute of Biological Sciences Ithaca Meeting September 1952 - General file - Hylander - Committee Organization, 1952-09 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  Correspondence; room assignments; list of participants; personal notes
- American Society for Horticultural Society Program - 1952, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  Program for the 1952 Ithaca meeting; participants, correspondence on attendance
- Sigma Xi 1945-1952, 1945-1952 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  Correspondence, committee reports, nominations
- Garden Clubs 1945-1956, 1945-1956 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Rochester Garden Center 1945-1949, 1945-1949 (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Laurence H. MacDaniels - American Society for Horticultural Science - Executive Committee - Dallas Meeting December 1941, 1941-12 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  Correspondence, program suggestions.
- American Society for Horticultural Science Publication Committee - W.H. Alderman, Chairman, Date Unknown (Box 3, Folder 46)
  Correspondence between Laurence H. MacDaniels and W.H. Alderman
- Screening Committee - Vaughn and Laurie Awards in Floriculture - 1954, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 47)
- American Society for Horticultural Science - Education Committee - R.A. VanMeter, Chairman, Date Unknown (Box 3, Folder 48)
  Correspondence between Laurence H. MacDaniels and R.A. VanMeter
- L.H. MacDaniels - American Society for Horticultural Science Meetings - 1940, 1939-1940 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  Correspondence 1939-1940; Committee reports 1939; copy of "Social Implications of Scientific Method" LHM
- American Society for Horticultural Science, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  Newsletters and correspondence 1954-1955
- Dr. Henry Munger, Editor American Society for Horticultural Science Proceedings 1950 and 1954, 1950-1954 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  Correspondence; essay on "New Name and Prospects for Macadamia in Hawaii" by J.H. Beaumont
- American Society for Horticultural Science - Committee for Grades and Standards 1953, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  Correspondence and Publications, research reports
- A.F Yeager - 1950-1951, 1950-1951 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Correspondence with Dr. A.F. Yeager of Department of Horticulture University of Hew Hampshire regarding various concerns of American Society for Horticultural Science with reference to Freeman Howlett
- American Society for Horticultural Science Committee on Education - 1950, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  Correspondence with Howlett and Yeager regarding appointment of L.H. MacDaniels to Education Committee as Chair
- American Society for Horticultural Science 1943-1954, 1943-1954 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Correspondence with Howlett; W. Reuther; LeRoy Holm; J. Carew; C.F. Williams; G.D. Oberle; M.J. Dorsey
- American Society for Horticultural Science Variety Committee - Older Material 1939-1950, 1939-1950 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Correspondence with F. Howlett; Committee on Varieties including R. Brooks; V.R. Boswell; S. Johnston; J.H. Weinburger; - T.R. Currence; S.L. Emsweller; G.H.M. Lawrence; R.L. Carolus; W.H. Upshall; G.M. Darrow; Katherine R. White; J.K. Shaw; W.H. Alderman; M.J. Dorsey; M.A. Blake; G.L. Slate; R. Wellington; H.B. Tukey; J.E. Knott; regarding Varieties Committee business including reports from Committee to American Society for Horticultural Science - (LHM elected president of ASHS 1940), personal notes and envelope containing 'Descriptive Blanks' for Variety Material. Not in chronological order
- American Society for Horticultural Science - Committee on Horticultural Nomenclature Taxonomy of Cultivated Plants 1951-1953, 1951-1953 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- American Society for Horticultural Science - Terminology - Horticulture Products and Services - Chadwick - Seeley 1951-1952, 1951-1952 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Correspondence with M.T. Fossum; F. Waugh; J.G. Seeley; L.C. Chadwick - regarding Committee on Terminology of American Society of Horticultural Science business - standardization in classification of Products and Services
- American Society for Horticultural Science - Horticultural Terminology - Howlett, Appointments - General Code 1951-1953, 1951-1953 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  Reports of Committee; "Economic taxonomy for Floriculture and Ornamental Horticulture" by M.T. Fossum; Standard Industrial Classification Manual Volume 2; personal notes; correspondence with F. Howlett; R.H. Roland; M.T. Fossum; R. Maqruder; R. Post; H. Munger; Superintendent of Documents, Washington, DC; R. Larson; D. Wyman
- American Society for Horticultural Science - Committee - Terminology - Horticultural Products and Services - Emsweller, Fossum 1951-1952, 1951-1952 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  Committee reports; personal notes; correspondence with R.P. White; R.H. Roland; B.A.E.; L.C. Chadwick; M.T. Fossum; J.G. Seeley; S.L. Emsweller
- American Society for Horticultural Science - Variety Committee - 1951 (1941-1951) (Not Chronological), 1941-1952 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  Committee reports and memos; personal notes; newsletters of American Society for Horticultural Science; "Simple provisional schedules of requirements for data essential to the typification of varieties of Horticultural plants." Appendix A - G.H.M. Lawrence. Correspondence with D.G. White; L.F. Hough; W.E. Snyder; S. Johnston; (committee list) L. Havis; F. Howlett; J.T. Breqqer; D.H. Scott; T.M. Currence; M.J. Dorsey; R.M. Brooks; V.R. Boswell; S.L. Emsweller
- American Society for Horticultural Science Committee - Terminology - Horticultural Products and Services - American Seed Trade Association - SAF, AAN, Bob Roland, Dick White 1951-1953, 1951-1953 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  Correspondence with F. Howlett; R.P. White; M.T. Fossum; S.L. Emsweller; L.C. Chadwick; J.G. Seeley; R.H. Roland; Wm. Heckendorn
- 13th International Horticultural Congress - 8-15 September 1952 (1951-1952), 1951-1952 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  Correspondence with C.V.L. Lycett, secretary of Royal Horticulture Society - regarding congress. 3 copies of Preliminary Programme
- Study of Occupational Retirement 1953-1956, 1953-1956 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  Correspondence with G.F. Streib; T.P. Wright; M.L. Barron and members of Study of Occupational Retirement Group letter from LHM; Notes on Retirement by LHM 10 Oct. 1954
- L.H. MacDaniels - Biographical sketch 1951, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  Correspondence with J.S. Knapp regarding Biographical material for Cornell University files; Who's Who in America; KC. Abbott copies of Biography
- Status with University 1941-1953, 1941-1953 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  Informational memos of status and salary changes
- McGraw-Hill Book Company 1950-1957, 1950-1957 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  Correspondence with various executives at McGraw-Hill (Eames and LHM) regarding publication of "An Introduction to Plant Anatomy" including royalties; new editions; English edition. Copy of IBM report of sales to bookstores
- McGraw-Hill Correspondence, 1933-1941 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  Regarding Book, also Royalty Statements 1933-1941
- Organic Gardening - Exhibit Material 1952, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  Various bulletins and publications from Organic Gardening, Emaus, PA; copy of manuscript "The Compost Pile" by LHM; copy of manuscript "Facts about Organic Gardening" by LHM; copy of manuscript "Truth about Organic Farming" by LHM; correspondence with W.B. Retz
- Plant Pathology Department Mimeographed Circulars on Flower Garden Diseases 1939-1945, 1939-1945 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Organic Gardening - Rural New Yorker 1952, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  Correspondence with W.B. Retz; M.M. Hyzer; D.E. Lewis; C.L. Devilbiss; A. Beusch; edition of Rural New Yorker from W.B. Retz; manuscript "Organic Farming - Truths, half-truths and Fallacies" January 1952 LHM published as "Truth about Organic Farming in Rural NY"
- Organic Gardening - Correspondence 1950-1954, 1950-1954 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  with C.E. Baker; R.I. Throckmorton; R.C. Allen; W.P. Judkins; M.H. McVickar; L.G. Klein; R. Rodale and Clarence Baker - re expose of Organic Gardening
- Personal Correspondence - Permanent 1943-1955, 1943-1955 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  Including L.H. Bailey; E.M. Hildebrand of Beltsville, MD; Emsweller; letter to Editor - regarding Fluoridation; Elmina Lucke; W.H. Chandler; A.J. Eames; W. Reuther; E.P. Imle; H.A. Rollins, D. Wyman
- A.J. Heincke - 1945, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- School of Horticulture at Farmingdale 1948-1955, 1948-1955 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Income Tax Material 1956, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Personal Recommendations - 1947-1955, 1947-1955 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Personal Correspondence - Current, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Sabbatic Leave - Commercial Concerns - Outboard Marine - Oceanic Forwarding 1950-1951, 1950-1951 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  New Caledonia, Canton Island
- (Envelope) Sabbatic Leave - Older Material - Letters to Bartlett 1947-1949, 1947-1949 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- New York State Flower Growers Bulletins 1945-1946, 1945-1946 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- A.W. Dimock Mimeos - Diseases Garden Flowers, Date Unknown (Box 4, Folder 30)
- D.S. Welch Tree Disease Mimeos, Date Unknown (Box 4, Folder 31)
  Copy - Floriculture 10 - Keys to Herbaceous Plants - G.H.M. Lawrence
- Dr. MacDaniels, 1947-03 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  Class trip of Floriculture 125 14-17 March 1947 (?)
- Miscellaneous Mimeographed Material - R.W. Curtis 1943, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Miscellaneous Floriculture Outlines, 1932-1946 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  "Artificial Keys to some Spring-Flowering Herbaceous plants" - J.F. Cornman 1946; "The Fall Planting of Hardy Bulbs" - R.C. Allen; "The Lily Family"; "Studies in the Family Orchidaceae" Wed. 29 April 1942; "Berried Plants for Birds and Woody Plants for Winter Effects" J.P. Porter Feb. 1925; "Thoughts of Christmas" - L.W.C. Tuthill May 14, 1930; "Prolonging the Keeping Qualities of Cut Flowers" Cleveland Flower Show March 13, 1932; "Genealogy of Modern Roses"; "Study of Color Harmonies"
- Camouflage 1942, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  Correspondence with various individuals and office of Civilian Defense and class outlines regarding camouflage
- Lab Outlines - Keys - R.W. Curtis, Date Unknown (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Personal 1, 1930-07-01-1931-06-30 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  To include all correspondence relating to strictly personal interests 1 July 30- 30 June 31; Including L.H. Bailey; R.F. Chandler; O.F. Curtis; all regarding personal agriculturally related busines
- Untitled - Notes about 'Lily Lecture', Date Unknown (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Contains handwritten notes on "lily lecture"
- Nursery Catalogues - 1938-1939, 1938-1939 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Including correspondence with J. Russell Smith (1939); Northern Nut Growers Association
- Leaf Structure - Summer 1933, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  1. Leaf structure in relation to photosynthetic activity, 2. General leaf structure under various conditions and treatments in relation to normal leaves and the structure of the leaves of different ages
- Leaf Development Study, Date Unknown (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Structure and Development of Leaf of Apple, Date Unknown (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Dr. Mac's Paper, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Notes from Foster, Adriance S. "Leaf Differentiation in Angiosperms - Botanical Review 2:349-72. 1936
- Flowers of Apple, Pear and Quince for Anatomical Study of Stomates and Glands and Grass Anatomy, Date Unknown (Box 5, Folder 8)
  hand written notes
- Apple Leaf - Tingley - Original Data - Stomates, Distances Btw. Veins - Drawings of Stomates, 1929 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  (Weeks Work 1929)
- L.H. MacDaniels - Mush Fe'I - Correspondence Recent, 1938-1942 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- 15. Research - from 1 July 35 - 30 June 36, 1935-07-01-1936-06-30 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  Correspondence regarding apple research
- 16. Bishop Museum and Musa Fe'I - from 1 July 35 - 30 June 36, 1935-07-01-1936-06-30 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- 9. Nuts - 1 July 34 - 30 June 35, 1934-07-01-1935-06-30 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  Correspondence regarding walnuts, hickories, butternuts, etc. with emphasis on general nut culture; with reference to G.L. Slate, individual correspondence with G.L. Slate (Sept. 34 - May 35) mostly alphabetical; also G.L. Smith
- 9. Nuts - from 1 July 35 - 30 June 36, 1935-07-01-1936-06-30 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  Correspondence regarding general nut culture, including grafting information; with correspondence with G.L. Slate (Oct. 35 - May 36) mostly alphabetical; much correspondence with G..L. Smith
- 9. Nuts - 1 July 33 - 30 June 34, 1933-07-01-1934-06-30 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  Correspondence regarding general nut culture including F.S. Howlett; National Nut Growers Association material; G.L. Slate (October 33-December 33); G.L. Smith; J. Russell Smith; alphabetical Folder in back: MacDaniels letters on nuts that require further correspondence or reference - scions (1932-33) mostly alphabetical
- Prints and Negatives, Date Unknown (Box 5, Folder 16)
  Envelopes of prints and negatives, some marked, 1 prints and negatives destroyed, nitrate negatives (kept out)
- 15. Research - Experiments Being Conducted, Planned Concluded 1 July 33 - 30 June 34, 1933-07-01-1934-06-30 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Pollen Dilnents (?) Photos, Date Unknown (Box 5, Folder 18)
- List of Negatives in File 2nd copy, Date Unknown (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Banana Research 1942-43, 1942-1943 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  Correspondence and bulletins, Envelope: adventitious bud - negatives and prints
- Drawings of Apple Flower, Date Unknown (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Structure of Pome Flowers, Date Unknown (Box 5, Folder 22)
  Hand written notes
- 9. Nuts - 1 July 32 - 30 June 33, 1932-07-01-1933-06-30 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  Correspondence regarding general nut culture - mostly alphabetical, Folder inside - no title - Correspondence regarding general nut culture, especially Scions - G.L. Smith, Large envelope of photographs: Anatomy - Miscellaneous Negatives, Some small envelopes labeled, some not, 1 destroyed. (nitrate negatives)
- Palmer Orchard - Hand Pollination - Results - Hilton, NY, Date Unknown (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Pollination Problems - W.A. Stalker 1935, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Pollination Data - J.R. Concklin, Date Unknown (Box 5, Folder 26)
  Including students' papers
- Pollination Notes 1937, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Pollination Notes and Records 1938-39, 1938-1939 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Nectar Concentration 1939, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Apple Fruit Abscission - L.H. MacDaniels, Date Unknown (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Pollination Research - Carl E. Vandeman, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  2 copies; 1 copy Orleans County Farm Bureau News, Vol. XXIV, No. 4, April 1939
- Apple Stippin - Anatomy of Pedicel, Date Unknown (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Skutt Orchard Yield 1934, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 33)
- Wound Treatment, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  Notes and copy, American Fruit Grower, March 1935 article on wound dressing
- Vessel Development in Robinia, Date Unknown (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Research Notes - Apple Histology and Anatomy, Date Unknown (Box 5, Folder 36)
  Hand written notes and drawings
- Cambial Growth with Resolution to Foliage Hookup and Gravity, Date Unknown (Box 5, Folder 37)
- Growth Measurements - With Relation to Shoot Position - MacDaniels - Curtis Project, Date Unknown (Box 5, Folder 38)
  Including prints and negatives, hand written notes
- L.H. MacDaniels - Commercial Hand Pollination 1935, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  Manuscript and working notes
- Curtis and MacDaniels - Sap Concentration of Grape, Date Unknown (Box 5, Folder 40)
- Apple Crotch Data - Manuscript and Procedure, Date Unknown (Box 5, Folder 41)
- Crotch Study - Data and Notes, Date Unknown (Box 5, Folder 42)
- Vessel Size - Kieffer Pear, Date Unknown (Box 5, Folder 43)
  Notes and manuscript
- 1. Personal - from 1 July 35 - 30 June 36, Expression (Box 5, Folder 44)
  Includes correspondence with L.H. Bailey; G.L. Slate; K.M. Wiegand; hand written notes of personal and professional nature, alphabetical
- 1. Personal - 1 July 34 - 30 June 35, 1934-07-01-1935-06-30 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  Includes correspondence with W.H. Chandler; E.F. Palmer; K.M. Wiegand; of personal and professional nature, alphabetical
- 1. Personal from 1 July 33 - 30 June 34, 1933-07-01-1934-06-30 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  Includes correspondence with "El Rosario," Mexico; G.L. Slate; alphabetical
- 1. Personal: to include all correspondence relating strictly to personal interests, from 1 July 32 - 30 June 33, 1932-07-01-1933-06-30 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  Including correspondence with E.F. Palmer; alphabetical including invoices from R. Wallace and Co., Ltd., etc.
- 1. Personal - to include all correspondence relating to strictly personal interests. To 30 June 1930., 1933-06-30 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  Including L.H. Bailey, C.E.F. Guterman; C.W. Savage; alphabetical
- 16. Research - Experiments being conducted, planned, concluded - 1 July 32 - 30 June 33, 1932-07-01-1933-06-30 (Box 5, Folder 49)
- Anatomical Study of Frost Damage Spring 1946, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 50)
- G.L. Slate 1950-1955 (not all chronological), 1950-1955 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- New Fruits Geneva Experiment Station - 1950, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  Bulletin on New Fruits; print-out on Amber Raspberry; print-out on Essex Strawberry
- Oberlin College Alumni Board 1950-51 (not chronological), 1950-1951 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  Correspondence - regarding board meetings and business; with D.T. Bradley, W.E. Stevens; R. Keesey
- Experiment Stations and Colleges 1943 and 1951, 1943-1951 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  Correspondence with various experiment stations including W.C. Chandler of University of California; G. W. Adriance of Texas A and M; - regarding exchange of horticulture business
- Code of Nomenclature, 1923 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  Code of Nomenclature of American Pomological Society - 1923 with revision 1937; correspondence with H.P. Gould of USDA - 1923
- L.H. MacDaniels - American 1956 for 1957 Volume, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  Horticulture Manuscript; bulletins: Agricultural Research from USDA 1956; Esso Fann News - 1956; American Horticulture Council Newsletter 1956; Molybdenum Agricultural Newsletter 1956; and various other newsletters
- Americana 1957, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  Hand written notes; articles on apples; correspondence with Massachusetts Horticultural Society 1956
- Americana Annual Source Material, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  Various agricultural bulletins 1956
- The Americana Annual - J.J.Smith, Editor, Progress in Horticulture - 1950-56 (not chronological), 1950-1956 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  Newspaper clippings; correspondence with J.J.Smith of American Annual of Encyclopedia Americana; newsletters; draft of article Horticulture (1954); draft of article Horticulture (1953); correspondence with Geneva Experiment Station (1953); draft of article Horticulture (1952); correspondence with Massachusetts Horticultural Society, draft of article Horticulture (1951 and 1950); correspondence with H.B. Tukey; draft of article Horticulture (1955)
- Sabbatic Leave - Personal, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  Hand written notes; correspondence with W.H. Chandler (1940)
- Fluoridation of Water Supply - 1954-56, 1954-1956 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  Correspondence regarding fluoridation of water
- New Hampshire Survey - 1951, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  "Evaluation of qualifications for graduate study leading to the doctorate degree. Departments of Botany and Horticulture, University of New Hampshire" and related correspondence
- McCay Bread 1952, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  Manuscript notes, assorted and correspondence - regarding Bread with C.McCay; various senators - regarding nutrition of bread and nutrition standards of Federal Food and Drug Administration
- L.H. MacDaniels - Color Photography Talk, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 14)
  Correspondence with Dr. Paul Arnold of ANSCO, including discussion of color photography processes
- Fishing 1951-1956, 1951-1956 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  Various bulletins and correspondence regarding fishing